<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elaborative Encoding</title><link>https://albertquiroga.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Elaborative Encoding</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Albert Quiroga</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 19:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://albertquiroga.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The "Spark writes too many output files" conundrum</title><link>https://albertquiroga.github.io/posts/spark-output-files-conundrum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://albertquiroga.github.io/posts/spark-output-files-conundrum/</guid><description>As a Big Data engineer, one of the most common problems I see people facing is &amp;ldquo;why is Spark writing 300 files&amp;rdquo;. Many engineers (specially ones in BI environments) are used to having datasets written as a single file, typically in a plain text format like CSV or JSON. Not only that, but many tools like Databases or BI dashboards expect data to be part of a single file - which obviously clases with how Spark works.</description></item><item><title>Controlling your Windows 10 PC with HomeKit</title><link>https://albertquiroga.github.io/posts/controlling-you-windows-10-pc-with-homekit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://albertquiroga.github.io/posts/controlling-you-windows-10-pc-with-homekit/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been going into a home automation spree, trying to automate my house as much as possible to avoid wasting time on repetitive stuff. While I am trying to not take it to the extreme, there&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot of nifty stuff you can either buy or quickly &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; with a Raspberry Pi to make your life much easier.
While I started by getting a cheap Echo Dot and running everything with Alexa, I quickly felt the system to be quite limited and messy - just like many other Amazon apps, the Alexa app has a very weird UI that seems to not have the main focus on home automation.</description></item><item><title>Elaborative encoding</title><link>https://albertquiroga.github.io/posts/elaborative-encoding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://albertquiroga.github.io/posts/elaborative-encoding/</guid><description>Why are kids in schools asked to write down what the teacher is saying?
We are in the age of personal computing, so this particular question might seem pretty stupid to you. Why do we have to use pen and paper to transcribe what the teacher is saying? My phone probably has access to hundreds of apps that can to speech-to-text for free, in a way that&amp;rsquo;s faster and more precise than I ever could.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://albertquiroga.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://albertquiroga.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hello!
My name&amp;rsquo;s Albert and I am an engineer currently living in Dublin, Ireland and working for AWS as a Big Data engineer.
Thanks for stopping by my personal blog. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to know how it started head to the first post, otherwise have a look around!
Regards,
Albert</description></item></channel></rss>